第 6 章：L。即使在词尾，舌尖也要碰到齿龈脊。
Chapter 6, the L. The tongue tip touches the ridge, even at the end of a word. This
本章讨论 L 音，不要和上一章讲过的美式 R 混淆。
chapter discusses the sound of L, not to be confused with that of the American R,
我们会先通过触及外国英语学习者面临的困难来接近这个音，
which was covered in the last chapter. We'll approach this sound first by
接着把 L 和相关的 T、D、N 音进行比较。
touching on the difficulties it presents to foreign speakers of English, and next
L 音以及英语学习者。
by comparing L to the related sounds of T, D, and N. L and foreign speakers of
英语 L 在词首或词中通常不是问题，
English. The English L is usually no problem at the beginning or in the middle
但有些人的母语会让他们在词尾
of a word. The native language of some people, however, causes them to make their
英语 L 发得太短。在词尾，如果 L 缺失或太短，会特别明显。
English L much too short. At the end of a word, the L is especially noticeable if it
另外，大多数人的 L 要么缺失，比如中文母语者；要么太短，比如西班牙语母语者。
is either missing, Chinese, or too short, Spanish. In addition, most people consider
这也会造成很多麻烦。
the L as a simple consonant. This can also cause a lot of trouble. Thus, two things
这里有两个因素在起作用：语言声音在口腔中的位置，以及 L 音的复杂性。
are at work here. Location of language sounds in the mouth, and the complexity of
先看语言声音在口腔中的位置。
the L sound. Location of language in the mouth. The sounds of many Romance
许多罗曼语族语言的发音位置通常非常靠口腔前部。我的法语老师
languages are generally located far forward in the mouth. My French teacher
他告诉我，说法语时如果看不见自己的嘴唇，那就不像法语。
told me that if I couldn't see my lips when I spoke French, it wasn't French.
西班牙语有时甚至被称为微笑语言。
Spanish is sometimes even called the smiling language. Chinese, on the other
另一方面，美式 L 与其类似，因为它主要在口腔后部
hand, is similar to American English in that it's mostly produced far back in the
主要区别在于，英语还要求清楚使用
mouth. The principal difference is that English It also requires clear use of the
舌尖，这是 L 音的重要组成部分。L 的复合音。
tongue's tip, a large component of the sound of L. The compound sound of L. The L
它不是一个简单辅音，而是由一个元音和一个辅音组成的复合音。
is not a simple consonant. It's a compound made up of a vowel and a consonant. Like
和 A 音一样，L 音是 uh 和 ul 的组合。
the a sound, the sound of L is a combination of uh and ul. The uh, being a
弱化元音是在喉咙里形成的，但 ul 这一部分需要清楚的
reduced vowel sound, is created in the throat, but the ul part requires a clear
舌头运动。首先，舌尖必须碰到牙齿后方。
movement of the tongue. First, the tip must touch behind the teeth. This part is
这一部分很简单。后舌必须向下、向后收。
simple enough. The back of the tongue must drop down and back for the continuing
这样才能为后续的 schwa 音留出空间。尤其在词尾，西班牙语母语者倾向于
schwa sound. Especially at the end of a word, Spanish-speaking people tend to
省掉 schwa，并把 L 缩短；中文母语者则通常会把它完全省掉。
leave out the schwa and shorten the L, and Chinese speakers usually leave it off
一种避免词尾 L的发音困难的方法，
entirely. One way to avoid the pronunciation difficulty of a final L, as
call 里的 L，要在下一个词以元音开头时和它连读。
in call, is to make a liaison when the next word begins with a vowel. For
例如，如果你想说 I have to call on my friend，就让连读替你完成
example, if you want to say, I have to call on my friend, let the liaison do your
这对你有帮助。比如说：I have to call on my friend。
work for you. Say, I have to call on my friend.